Morning. It's the program with Ted Roll
and John Kuryaku. It's Tuesday, November
4th, 2025. It's election day in New York
City, New Jersey, and across the nation.
Uh, and we are uh looking forward to
seeing those results. John, good to see
you.
>> Good to see you, Ted. It's uh it's
election day here in Virginia as well.
>> Excellent. So, lots to talk about. You
know, John, um this morning when I woke
up, I kind of noticed that the sun was a
little brighter.
>> Yes. I noticed that the birds were
singing more beautifully than ever.
>> Yes. And there was automatically an
extra spring in my step.
>> My my my cat's fur was glistening,
almost sparkling. Um my my I just felt
like probably my bank account increased
a little bit. Um just everything just
seemed brighter. And then I woke up to
the news that the the dark lord had had
passed onto whatever uh horrible
dimension he resides in.
>> Uh Dick Cheney of course is dead, former
vice president and uh we'll get into uh
you know his legacy. I'm sure you of all
people have thoughts. I have many
thoughts. The Bush years were very
formative for both of us. Um so we're
going to talk about Dick Cheney. We'll
talk about uh Israel's very, as I called
it, very wrong scandal. So, uh you can
identify with this. Uh a top army lawyer
uh ratted out the IDF for sticking a
knife up a Palestinian's ass and
sodomizing him. That got caught on
video. Yeah. She she leaked it. She
leaked it because nothing was going to
happen to the rapists um and and
basically attempted murderers. Yes. Um,
and so they decided to do the right
thing and put her in prison. Okay.
Instead of giving her a promotion,
>> the wonderful world of whistleblowing.
>> Indeed. Like, well, we have so much in
common with Israel that way. Uh, Chaos
at the Heritage Foundation over Tucker
Carlson's interview with Nick Fuentes.
Um, Africa continues to blow up. I'm
proud of our show for talking about
Africa, you know, as much as it
deserves. Maybe not enough, but uh, now
it's Tanzania. Things are pretty crazy
over there. We'll try to break that down
for you. Um, you know, I just want to
say I I came up with the AI generated
thumbnail for the Dick Cheney thing. I
just want to be clear that the idea that
he's in in heaven with like the angel
was meant to be a sarcastic joke.
>> When I saw that, I was like, should I
call Ted this morning? [laughter]
>> No, he probably did it on purpose for
some reason. I just thought it would be
funny as [__] because I didn't want to
go with the obvious like he's turning
crispy brown by now.
>> Well, I wanted to say something, too.
There's a there's a quote that is
attributed to Mark Twain. It is
attributed incorrectly to Mark Twain.
People believe that Mark Twain said,
"I've never wished a man dead, but I
have read some obituaries with great
pleasure."
>> Yes.
>> Clarence Darrow actually said it.
>> Oh, that's great. and he should get
credit for it. But that was literally
the first thought in my head when I
rolled over this morning to see what the
push notification was on my phone and it
said that Dick Cheney was dead. Like
you've said, uh, Ted, um, you know, we
all have thoughts about Dick Cheney.
I've been in meetings with Dick Cheney
in which I have like feared for my
safety.
>> Wow. because he would lose his [__] like
a crazy person in these meetings and
then he would get up and storm out and
then everybody would be like, "Okay,
well, back to work." And then they would
get up like it was normal to treat
people like that.
>> Wow. And when it came to, let's let's
enumerate them. The assassination
program, the torture program, the
rendition program, the secret prison
program, literally all of it was Dick
Cheney. All of it. It was all his idea.
And they were all implemented by people
who were close to him.
That's his legacy in this country. His
legacy is is the stripping of the
Constitution,
ignoring of human rights, and uh making
our country weaker while pretending that
he was making it stronger.
>> Yeah. I mean, he's the he's the hatchet
man of uh neoconservatism, right? He's
not a a neoconservative theorist like uh
you know like some like uh like like
well like like people who signed the
original project for a new American
century letter um you know uh like like
a John Keegan type person. He's more um
you know he was but he's the guy who
really made it happen. He had this idea
like literally as within hours of the
attack on 911, he was approaching people
in the White House saying like, "Okay,
we're going to invade Iraq now."
>> Yeah.
>> Confused, right? Iraq.
>> That's right.
>> What did they have to do with this? What
could they have had to do with this?
>> Nothing. Literally.
>> I mean, Saddam Hussein and Iraq hated Al
Qaeda. Al Qaeda wanted to overthrow.
>> Yes.
Yes. Indeed. So I mean, so he was the
biggest architect of of the lies. I mean
him and Donald Rumsfeld uh the lie
machine. Donald Rumsfeld had my favorite
lies of my and there were so many to
choose from. My favorite one was we know
exactly where the WMDs are. They are
north, east, south, or west of Baghdad
somewhat.
[laughter]
You could look it up.
>> You know, it's funny. Rumsfeld.
Cheney was a Cheney was an intern in
Rumsfeld's office when Rumsfeld was a
congressman. That's how they met.
Rumsfeld was a congressman, I think,
from Illinois. [snorts] And Cheney
really, really, really wanted to go to
Washington. He was a he was from
Wyoming. He had three DUIs in his past.
Couldn't find a job, but really loved
Rumsfeld. So he applied for this
internship and he he got this low-level
entrylevel internship in Rumsfeld's
office and Rumsfeld really took to him.
And then um when when Rumsfeld became
Secretary of Defense for the first time,
uh Cheney was in his first term in
Congress. This was during the Ford
administration. And Rumsfeld recommended
to Ford, hey, you should hire Cheney as
your chief of staff. He's a real tough
son of a [__] And so Cheney became
Gerald Ford's chief of staff. Set
himself apart in conservative circles
once Ford lost to Carter and then came
roaring back with uh with Reagan and
Bush and the rest is history.
>> That is Yeah. I mean that's that's the
thing, right? The origin story of the
Bushies really goes back to the Ford
administration where all of those people
came together. Um I mean I guess they
didn't have much to do because uh for
people who don't know like Jerry Ford
was probably uh you know he he dealt
with a uh 1974 huge Democratic sweep and
so basically Congress wouldn't pass
anything that he proposed and he
wouldn't and he vetoed everything that
Congress you know
>> pass they called him president veto.
>> Yeah. Nothing happened. I mean,
basically all he he was basically widely
known for the pardon and for whip
inflation now buttons.
>> Yeah, I still have mine.
>> I still have mine, too. Um, you know, so
uh question that came up from Fuso and
I'm glad that he brought this up because
uh uh he said uh thanks for the donation
by the way. Over under number of years
till Cheni is whitewashed as a good guy.
I think it's zero. I think we're we're
there right now. I mean already the
media is uh whitewashing him as like you
know he's a he was a he he was progay he
came out in favor of his daughter which
>> eventually eventually only because it
split his family
>> right
>> not because he had any love of gays
>> not [snorts] at all right he was very
very right-wing in all the worst ways
and uh you know and and he liked to fly
fish who gives a [__] that he liked to
fly fish but they're trying to humanize
this bastard
Um, I mean, and he was just, uh, you
know, I mean, I I thought there's so
many things to say about Dick Cheney,
all of them mostly bad. My favorite was
that Bush put, you know, basically
picked him as the head of his vice
presidential search running mate search
committee, uh, because he wanted
someone, you know, he's like he didn't
really know who to choose. And um so he
so Jeanie finally was like well I looked
around and I'm thinking me
and that's literally how he became he
was the head of he picked himself.
>> Yeah he did.
>> So
>> yeah he did and you know there's
>> what kind of man
>> in the movie Vice there's a there's a
scene where where Bush is asking him to
be vice president where where Cheney
made it look like it was Bush's
decision. So he said, "Well, I would
want to be in charge of foreign affairs,
defense policy." Bush says done. Energy
policy, trade,
uh, done. Uh, tax policy, the
environment, done.
And then he's like, "Okay, then we have
an agreement."
>> And also he wanted like really frequent
meetings, right? Like like
>> Yeah. You know, that's another thing.
It's it's rather unusual for the
president and vice president to meet
more often than once a week. Usually,
they'll have breakfast together on a
Tuesday and then go over what the rest
of the week is looking like. Cheney and
Bush met every single day in the Oval
Office for the president's daily brief
and then Cheney essentially would tell
Bush, "This is what is happening in
foreign policy. This is what's happening
at DoD." you know, Cheney was obviously
clearly the president.
>> Did I mean, yeah. No, I think I think
anyone who lived through that period has
to agree with that. Um, I mean, I guess,
you know, I want to be fair here. To
what extent was Bush responsible? I
mean, was Bush a dupe or was he or did
or was he just lazy or is it something
else that happened in this dynamic? I
hate to say it, but in my own personal
experience, and I saw them interacting
with each other, and and I I mean, you
know, my positions at the CIA at the
time, I I had access to these guys all
the time. Bush was a dum dum. I hate to
say it, but there's no other way to say
it. He was just an idiot. He was like
the village idiot who somehow found
himself in charge of the village. And so
Cheney knew that. Cheney took advantage
of it. and Cheney put himself in charge
and made it look like Bush was in was in
charge.
>> That's Yeah, I mean it's it's really
kind of insane. And you know, and then
he talked the American people. Well, I
mean, a lot of them talked to the
American people, right? And they all had
their roles, right? Coen Powell closed
the deal with that speech in front of
the United Nations with the fake vile.
>> Absolutely right. Um, I've always
thought, you know, my my fantasy, John,
was that uh in the Hollywood version of
that, and I bet I bet Coen Powell had
this dream at least once before he died.
Um, you know, he starts to give the
speech. They told him, "Go up there and
do it." He knew it was all [__] at
the time. It was reported that he spent
the weekend really angry and frustrated
when he read over all the evidence and
he was like, "There's nothing here." And
at one point, he threw it all up. I
don't remember if it was Time or
Newsweek. One of them reported that he
threw everything up in the air and said
this is all [__] But he went out
there and did it anyway because
>> when Cyrus Vance was Secretary of State
and the president told him to say
something he didn't believe in. Cyrus
Vance resigned.
>> Co should have resigned.
>> And that's and and he could have done it
at the UN. What if he had gone to the UN
and just said they sent me out to they
sent me out here to lie to the American
people and to the people of the world
and I will not do it.
>> [clears throat]
>> He would have been president in 2004.
>> He would have been president. You know,
Larry Wilkerson is a friend of many of
ours, right? And Larry was Colin Pal's
best friend and his chief of staff when
he was the secretary of state. They came
up through the military together. They
served for years together in the
military. And then when Ronald Reagan
was president, Colin Powell went from
Lieutenant Colonel to fourstar general
in four years.
Like George Washington didn't get
promoted that quickly, but Reagan took
to Colin Powell and made Colin Powell
somebody. And Larry will tell you that
in their private moments together, Colin
Powell would admit that he was in over
his head. He shouldn't have been
promoted so quickly and that
he was weak when it came to the weapons
of mass destruction debate. Colin Pal
said to Larry at the time and said in
his memoirs years later that he should
have resigned that he ruined his
reputation by going along with what Bush
and Cheney and Rumsfeld wanted him to
say. Yeah. And it was the gravest
mistake of his life. I think that was in
his character. I think frankly, John,
John, that was baked into his character.
Because he was the PR flack who was put
in charge to go out and sell [__]
about the Mi massacre during the Vietnam
War. Go out and tell the press the line
of [__] about like nothing happened,
nothing to see here. This is why I have
always said that I don't think military
officers
especially generals should have cabinet
level positions anywhere because how did
they make four stars? They made it by
saying yes sir for 30 or 35 years. And
what you need in positions like that is
someone who has the guts to stand up and
say Mr. President that is a terrible
idea. Let me explain to you why. And
that was not Colin Powell.
>> No, it wasn't. John, we've got an ad, so
I'm gonna go ahead and read that.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Outdoor crew, if you're into
fishing, camping, or getting off the
grid, meet your new best friend, the
Hunter Orange 25Q cooler from Catis
Sports. This isn't your average cooler.
It's roto molded for max durability.
Bearproof, and 20% lighter than other
brands, so it's easier to haul. Whether
you're deep in the back country or just
setting up at the dock, you'll get up to
three days of ice retention thanks to
thick, high performance insulation. That
means cold drinks, fresh food, and fewer
ice runs, whether you're chasing muttons
offshore or posted up at a campsite.
Best part, it's 40 to 50% cheaper than
the bigname coolers, but still be built
to perform season after season. And like
all Catis Sports name brand gear, it's
proudly made in the USA. Use code rumble
at checkout for 10% off your order
today. That's catis c- a ddisports.com.
Go grab the Hunter Orange 25Q cooler and
keep your next adventure ice cold.
>> You know, I I was very proud last night.
Uh Ted, I two friends of mine and I
released episode three of a podcast I
have on on Apple Podcast called Deadrop.
What makes a spy tick? So, we dropped
our third episode and knock on wood,
I've been so fortunate that last night,
much to my shock when I listened to it,
it says, "Dead drop, what makes a spy
tick? Brought to you by Progressive
Insurance." And I was like, "What?
Progressive Insurance." So, I called one
of my colleagues who's the producer. I
said, "Hey, what did we make now that
we're endorsed by Progressive
Insurance?" He said, "Let me look it
up." So, we looked it up. $22, buddy.
>> Excellent. [laughter]
>> All right. Well, you know, $22 and you
know, it's like, look, what would you
do? Would would [laughter] you The way
you have to look at it is if you saw $22
lying on the ground, would you pick it
up?
>> Yeah. And you'd be very happy to.
>> I have to split it three ways, but
that's $7.33
I didn't have yesterday. [laughter]
>> That's how you have to look at it. Um,
let's do a little bit of housekeeping
here. So, for people who uh are regular
viewers, you know that our producer
Robbie uh West, who uh was doxed out of
his current job um and basically uh will
be out of that work in two weeks. Um he
is uh going to be rejoining the show
here and that's the good news. Um, but
the bad news, or maybe it's the good
news, is that you have the opportunity,
as NPR would say, to help contribute to
making this show viable by making his
tenure as producer viable for us.
Please, we we basically need for this to
work to keep Robbie going month after
month. We need a grand a month from him.
That means we need a grand a month from
you guys. John and I are we are each
paying 250. Just so full transparency
here. So, it's not like we're asking you
for stuff that we're not willing to
contribute. And we're both broke as
[__] but we're paying but we're paying
250 a month. So, if you guys can do,
we're each doing 250. If you guys can do
a,000, that'd be awesome. Please go to
giveendgo.comwestgaming.
Again, that's giveendgo.
Not not the other one.
Givego.comwestglacaming.
and throw some money uh Robbiey's way.
We will keep doing this until we get to
the thousand dollars for November. Then
we'll shut the [__] up until December.
So basically that is our our our pledge
to you. So if someone goes in and sends
in a grand right now, the whole thing's
over. So you know who you are. You
people are we have we have some rich
viewers. So you know whatever.
>> Um
is it is it worth before we move on from
Dick Cheney, I think it's impossible to
overstate his legacy, right? Um well
what let's talk about let's talk about
Trump a little bit. Um what's Trump's
view of Bush and Cheney? I mean Trump
late he you know he he's he's a little
bit revisionist about this. He he came
to opposing the Iraq war sort of after
um but you know before a lot of other
Republicans and he remarkably ran
against the Iraq war in in as a
Republican primary candidate in 2016.
Is Donald Trump um going to order flags
placed at half staff? Is is he going to,
you know, have a big to-do body and
state at the at the uh at the capital?
Is he going to make a big to-do about
it? Or is he going to basically do what
he what Jean deserves and have his body
thrown into a dumpster? I have no inside
information, of course, like you have no
inside information, but my guess is in
order to try to shore up the neocon wing
of the Republican party, the answer is
probably yes. He'll probably do a lot of
those things. We have not had a vice
president
lay in state in the capital since Hubert
Humphrey. Uh Hubert Humphrey died in
1978.
>> So, it's been a long time. I would be
afraid, frankly, that if he were lying
in state, no one would show up.
[laughter]
>> I'm serious.
>> People might come by just to make sure
he's dead.
>> Just just jab him with a fork to make
sure he's dead.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Yeah. No, it could be. Yeah. Yeah. I
mean, that's a good question. Do people
come to uh pay their respects really to
pay their respects or do they come out
of idle curiosity or both?
>> I think most of them come out of uh
curiosity. Um, I've been to a bunch, but
never out of curiosity, only out of
respect. I went uh I went to Claude
Pepper, for example.
>> Um, but there were others that I
skipped. I skipped Ronald Reagan. I
loathed Ronald Reagan. It I felt like I
would be hypocritical if I went to stand
in line and walk past the He just walked
past a closed casket with a flag over
it. So, big deal. What do you see?
>> Um,
>> yeah. Nothing. It's just a box.
>> Yeah. Um, I went to Jimmy Carter. I had
a lot of respect for Jimmy Carter even
though he refused to uh write a letter
of support for my pardon application. I
went back and forth with his chief of
staff a half a dozen times. My lawyers
are writing and they're like, "Nah, he
doesn't want to do this."
>> You know, I don't even understand that,
right? Like it's sort of like if you
have a I mean, I would be a pardon [__]
if
>> I would too.
>> Yeah. [snorts]
>> Yes.
>> It's like why not? Like why not like
throw people a bone? Like when people
ask me for a a book blurb, um I used to
be a book blurb [__] People ask me all
the time. Oh yeah. I was like, you know,
if I could help you sell your book,
unless it's something I really despise.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. I never say no to book blurbs.
I've written a dozen of them, I guess.
[clears throat] Happy to do it.
>> Yeah, totally.
>> And I've written three or four forwards
and afterwards and stuff for other
people's books. Happy to do it. When my
my my
inclination whenever somebody asks me
for something, even people I don't even
know, my inclination is to say yes
because you never know. You know, you
spreading goodwill, maybe it'll come
back to you.
>> Phil is asking if we've both been do are
we both doxed? Pretty lame thing to do
to a person. Um I would I mean, you
know, I would say I have not been I
don't want to give anyone any ideas. I
would say I've not been I look I get
death threats.
>> I get death threats. I got a half a
dozen of them last week.
>> Yeah,
>> that was an unusual week though.
>> But yeah, I haven't been doxed, but I
get death threats with some regularity.
>> I don't think doxing would do would do
anyone any good since I don't work for
any like
>> mainstream organizations that like would
get pissed off at me or fire me or
anything like that. Um, you know, my
syndicate they, you know,
>> to quote Jonathan Richmond, they know
who I am. Um, they've they've had been
dealing with me with my annoying ass
since 1996. See? Um, so you know, I'm
I'm Go ahead, Docs OA. You know,
nothing's going to happen there.
>> Same here.
>> Uh, let's see. Um, FUZ wants to know
what bands are lined up to perform at
Robbie Aid.
>> I don't know. Probably. I would imagine
uh some right-wing bands. Not the Dixie
Kit. The Chicks maybe. Aren't they just
called the Chicks now? Something.
>> Yes, they're the chicks because it's I
guess uh racist to say Dixie.
Oh, well this is funny. Uh, Rebellious
Rainbow Unicorn. Nice to see you. So, we
should write in published Darth Cheni's
real obituary and publish it. Um, yeah.
Now, I'm looking forward to seeing like
what the New York Times has got going.
Um, you know, I think they'll probably
do a good job. Their obituaries are are
legend.
>> The the the New York Times always has
the best obituaries. The post obituary
today was generally factual.
Slightly on the procheny
side.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. God, that's crazy. I don't even
know how you can do that. I mean, you
know, his approval rating when he died
was like one like 9% or something like
that.
>> See,
>> he and Eric Adams.
>> Yeah. Both of them.
>> Um, couldn't
>> Thanks for the donation, Phil Chats.
>> In their own households.
>> Phil Chats just gave us five bucks.
Appreciate it.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Um would like our
thoughts on hm frog shack gamers wants
to know would like your thoughts on
meshtast meshtastic and if private
decentralized communication networks are
the future to combat invasion of
privacy.
>> I I'm only peripherilally
um aware of uh of these issues but you
know we should have we should have Sean
O'Brien on. He could walk us through it
step by step.
>> Let's do that. Okay. We will do that. F
you. So, thank you for the buck. Uh, in
case Cheney in the new Trump [laughter]
White House ballroom coat rack or
something. Yeah, maybe like in a like in
a like in a like a bear attacking.
>> Yeah,
>> throw your coat on top there. Yeah,
that's that. I could I could handle
that. Um,
here we go. Uh, Riz Rizwan Hassan 9757.
Do I have to make an account on Rumble
for us to benefit from watching videos
on Rumble? Um,
>> I don't think so.
>> I don't think so either.
>> I don't think so. I think just so long
as you watch it, that's what counts.
>> Yeah, we're Watch hours are king. We're
gonna find out a little more about the
the metrics here. Oh, uh, Katie
Catastrophe, too. They people can never
believe this is true, right? Oh, that
[clears throat] there's chat GPT still
has no record of me. Google says it's
because of your controversial LA
newspaper stuff. Yeah, that's not why.
It's because of uh an article uh that I
wrote in the Wall Street Journal making
fun of Open AI and Sam Alman.
>> Yes, without a doubt. Yes,
>> because that's when it happened. I mean
LA Times thing that was I was I was all
over chat GPT and years after the LA
Times thing was all over. Um have we
seen Born to Battery wants to know, have
we seen the SNL White House improvement
skit? No. Um I've had a lot going on.
Uh, but I'm uh I I need to catch up on
that. I always SNL to me is it's it's
it's a shitty show. I mean, I just got
to say it's kind of it's always been a
shitty show, but there's always like one
skit
>> that you should kind of watch.
>> They're never that it's never that good.
>> No,
>> but it'll have moments. I can't believe
this shitty show's been running for 50
years. Like,
>> you know, on a on the plane the other
day, I was flying back from somewhere
Mexico, I guess. I was flying back from
Mexico and and I'm going through the you
know the entertainment on the back of
the seat and there was um there was
something about uh needs more cowbell
you know the famous skit with
Christopher Walkin needs more cowbell
>> here's how desperate Saturday Night Live
has become
>> it was it was an hourong documentary on
the skit
>> what needs needs more cowbell
>> ridiculous
That's how desperate they are. And then
they the people that they're
interviewing were like,
"Oh, uh, yeah." Are you You're saying
you're making a documentary just on the
skit?
>> This was good. Yeah. It's not It's not
like that documentary they made on that
uh The Aristocrats, you know, about the
joke.
>> No. No. That's right. The joke,
>> right? The worst joke in the world or
the most
>> The aristocrats.
>> The dirtiest joke in the world. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I mean I don't understand like
the I mean SNL makes me actually crazy.
It's literally like is there something
wrong with me that like I'm just stone
cold like just not laughing while I'm
watching this and what does every what
is it that everyone else sees that I
don't see and it makes me crazy. uh
toward that end like a few months ago I
went back and I started watching SNL
from starting with season one episode
one and uh you know it's and it's kind
of like okay it was better then
>> but it wasn't that great.
>> No
>> really.
>> No.
>> And it's all that's a good way to put
it. That's a good way to put it. It was
better then but it was never really
great. Like you say, you can pull out
individual hilarious skits and put them
together in a best of DVD, but
>> now Carol Bernett's show was hilarious.
>> Great. [laughter]
>> Yeah. Like Yeah. And consistently.
>> Yes.
>> I mean, you know, even in living L
living color
>> that had a lot of good [__]
>> A lot. and and made people giant stars.
>> Laughing a lot of funny [__]
[clears throat]
>> Classic.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I mean, it's we can do humor. SNL
>> Smother's brothers even. Yeah.
>> I I just can't. Yeah. I mean, so yeah,
and it's like Yeah, it's horrible.
Anyway, um hell, someone should just do
skits making fun of SNL.
>> Uh what we All right, we got we got a
half hour left here on our show. I I
love how fast it goes, but um but then I
hate how fast it goes. Um so what do you
want to talk about? Heritage Foundation,
Israel?
>> Yeah, let's talk about the Heritage
Foundation. Um there's a real there's a
real split right now in the Heritage
Foundation that appears to have been
caused by Tucker Carlson. Tucker
Carlson,
you know, I I've said it a million
times. He's a friend of mine, and he he
said something to me the other day that
made me very happy for him. He feels
utterly unencumbered by anything or
anybody. He's rich. He's famous. He
doesn't work for anyone.
>> He controls his own destiny.
>> Controls his own destiny. He's got the
Tucker Carlson network. He can say
whatever the [__] he wants to say. And
people don't like that. And at the
Heritage Foundation, they don't like it
because he had Nick Fuentes on the other
day. Now, me personally, I wouldn't have
had Nick Fuentes on, but that's just me.
I don't know what I'd want to say to the
guy. He's only like 25 years old. Yeah.
>> He he became a household name because of
his racism.
>> Um so I wouldn't really have anything to
say to him, but Tucker had him on
>> and um and in the course of the
conversation they kind of pulled the
Heritage Foundation in and uh it's it's
gotten ugly the last couple of days.
>> Well, so the her I mean so it's strange,
right? So, the Heritage Foundation is a
right-wing think tank, most notably uh
recently for Project 2025, but
>> it it's the best funded right-wing think
tank in America.
>> It also is is what Obamacare came out
of, right? Obamacare, I mean, Heritage
came up with Romney Care, which became
the AC, the Affordable Care Act. Um, but
it was like sort of like above, it used
to be above or it seemed to be above the
GOP fray. It was like conservative
rather than Republican.
>> That's correct.
>> Now it's Republican.
>> Yes.
>> And um and that seems to be that seems
to have been a mistake. I bet
>> the same thing happened at Liberty
University where it it was they were
very proud to say that they would turn
out conservative Christians and now they
say that they're proud to turn out
Republican Christians.
>> That's Yeah, that's always a mistake.
Same
>> yeah same thing with like uh
>> when uh when there's you know there's
far fewer similar organizations on the
left among liberals but uh you know when
they become democratic organs I mean I
feel like that happens like the nation
became democratic as opposed to
>> very much so
>> progressive
>> that's exactly right
>> and once that happens you're you're
[__] done all right so what exactly
is this about right so basically Tucker
interviews Nick Nick Fuentes so [__]
what I mean Okay, I understand why
people would get upset, particularly
liberals. Yeah. Um, you know, um, I I
interviewed when I was when I was at had
my radio show in LA at KFI, I
interviewed David Duke for three hours.
It was supposed to be an hour and it was
just it was going so great with all the
lots of calls. I was just like, keep
going, keep going, keep going. It's a
fantastic three hour, you know, great. I
mean, here's, you know, you don't really
know much about David Duke. You listened
to those three hours though, you
definitely understood why he actually
really was dangerous because he was so
charismatic, so funny, so intelligent.
Yeah. Um, and so very dangerous guy. Um,
good-looking, too. And fun and, you
know, I I liked him. That's a funny I
mean, I hated everything he had to say,
but I liked him.
>> Um, so I mean, isn't isn't that just uh
is Dwat Tucker guilty of doing
journalism? I mean, I like you, I
wouldn't have interviewed Nick Fuentes
because I don't really think there's
much to learn about this little
pipsqueak.
>> No, I agree. And we have a a question
from um Craig D. Vance who says,
"Honestly, why do you guys support
Carlson after all the stuff he did on
Fox?" Honestly asking for me personally,
he was he he has consistently been one
of my strongest supporters from the very
beginning from my from my arrest. And um
just secondarily um he was one of the
first Republicans to really call the
Israelis out on on human rights abuses
in in Gaza and the West Bank and I had
respect for that. Plus he's a very sweet
guy. You know, you you don't have to
agree with everything. I actually
disagree with most things. That's
something that he said on his show. He
said, "You and I probably disagree on
90% of the issues." But he said, "I like
you and we're friends." That's how I
feel about him.
>> Now, I've never met Tucker Carlson. I've
never been on a show. Would love to be.
Uh, but the thing is that he's uh, you
know, I mean, I've watched him for years
and you know, I used to find his bow tie
stick really annoying. U, generally
people with bow ties, it's like, why are
you wearing a bow tie? My best friend
Scott's dentist when I met him, he used
to wear bow ties. I was like, why the
[__] are you wearing bow ties? U, but
that said, uh, yeah, it's just same, you
know, same thing. Look, he strikes me as
a guy who has integrity, which is to say
not that he's always right. No.
>> But that he is trying to find out what
the truth is within, you know, the the
limits of we all have our limits of
politics and personality and and so on.
And that's to me that's all I can ever
ask. And here's the I mean he's one of
the rare media personalities who ever
admits when he's mistaken. So, um, you
know, so I wouldn't say I support him,
but I would be like, I respect him,
which is more important.
>> Yeah, that's how I feel.
>> Yeah. And I I think one of the reasons
why conservatives are afraid of him
right now is because he is way more
powerful in media than he ever was at
Fox.
and um and because he's given the
Israelis [__] and the Israelis aren't
sure how to react to it
>> and Lord knows they [__] deserve it.
Yeah. Um Oello has a question for us. I
don't know. Uh they want he wants to
know our thoughts on uh Zoran Mandani.
Um well um the elections today he's
going to be the mayor of the city of New
York. He's going to be a boy mayor, 34
years old. He's going to about to defeat
Andrew Cuomo who's 67 years old. Uh and
the former governor, three-term governor
of the state. Uh you know, political
lion is that's pretty much I think going
to mark the end of Cuomo's uh political
career. I mean, I could see, by the way,
if there were a Democratic president in
the future, I could see Cuomo ending up
on the cabinet. Um easily.
>> Sure.
>> Uh you know,
>> I could see I could see Cuomo ending up
in a Republican cabinet.
>> I could see that, too. Oh, by the way,
Donald Trump just endorsed Cuomo.
>> I saw that. yesterday afternoon.
>> By the way, that's the death of him.
>> Kiss of death done.
>> Yeah, that's just just five points just
of his 25 just evaporated in
>> and Curtis Lee was like, "Fuck you,
Trump."
>> Yeah, that's [laughter] No, that's
disgusting. What did Curtis Leewa do to
deserve that? Curtis Leewa is the
Republican
>> Republican nominee.
>> [__] Donald Trump. That's so That's so
[__] wrong. But
>> I bet Cuomo's even thinking, "Fuck
Donald Trump." Um, you know, because
it's also one of those things like if it
was going to do any good, it might have
done more good months ago. That's right.
>> Um, I think Mandani is a promising young
man. He's definitely in over his head.
He's 34 years old. Um, hopefully he'll
surround himself with um some some smart
and uh good people. Um, you know, I
think he seems he seems smart enough to
know what he doesn't know. What do you
think?
>> Yeah, I think that's right. And you
know, one of the things that has been
largely ignored about Mamani is that he
has surrounded himself with very smart
people, many of whom, and this is
something the media I think are are
purposely ignoring, many of whom happen
to be Jewish. And so this nonsense that
he's an anti-semite,
um I think is not is not working. There
I saw a clip yesterday from one of the
early mayoral debates where there were
like six candidates and the question was
where will your first if when you're
elected mayor where will your first
foreign trip be
like Israel Israel Israel Israel Israel
and Mamani said um I am happy to meet
with Jewish voters in all of the five
buraus my job would be to be as mayor of
of uh uh New York, not to enact a
foreign policy like I'm secretary of
state. If if uh constituents happen to
be Jewish, I'm happy to meet with them.
If they happen to be Muslim or happen to
be Christian, I'm happy to meet with
them. Their religion makes no difference
to me. And then they start screaming
with Cuomo being the loudest. That's
anti-Semitic.
You don't support Israel. Screaming.
It's like, no, that's not at all what he
said. He's going to be mayor of New
York. He's not going to be secretary of
state.
>> No.
>> So, who cares where his first trip is
going to be?
>> Well, and you know who who kind of gets
to decide this is New York's high Jewish
population.
>> Exactly.
>> And guess what? New York's high Jewish
population overwhelmingly supports
Mamani.
>> Yeah. It's crazy.
>> So, they do. In fact, you know who else
in the entire the Jewish population of
the United States is opposed to Israel
and prob ballast Palestinian now.
>> Game over Israel. You guys are finished.
You're done. Like
>> that is right.
>> So all right. So do do we want to move
on past? So let's talk about Israel. It
seems like a good place to to transition
here.
>> Yeah. Um, so Major General Yafat Tomer
Yeser Shami uh is a top army lawyer I
guess. Would you say that she was a JAG
kind of like a top Jag?
>> Yes.
>> Equivalent. So she basically um got came
across a well she was she was on she had
access to the surveillance tape that
showed IDF soldiers um at at this
notorious torture facility. I don't know
how you pronounce it, but today tan. Um,
but basically uh they were sodomizing a
Palestinian uh uh prisoner with a knife.
Um, not shockingly, he was uh severely
injured and had to be uh go through
numerous surgeries. He got rectile
perforation and they fractured his his
ribs. He's lucky to be alive.
>> Yeah, he's lucky to be alive. And um
anyway, so shock shockingly and
strangely, rather than uh having a
grateful nation uh thank thank her and
say, "Well, thank you for uh you know,
revealing this." She sent this to the
media because obviously nothing was
happening internally. Um most of the
country, which has gone so far rightwing
that it's crazy, they're pissed at her
>> and um and they want her to stay in
prison.
uh another former prosecutor, Matan
Solomesh, also um is in prison for
related charges. Um you know, so and
then Netanyahu's allies are saying
things like now we can resume the lynch.
In other words, they want to they you
know, there was some thought that she
might have committed suicide. She kind
of like van v vanished and she went off
to the beach. and that that whole
episode sort of feels like uh you know
being on the Appalachian Trail if you
remember that episode. Um but who knows
what was going on here. Look you the
stress can absolutely make you
contemplate suicide. Um you know you and
I have talked about that and uh we've
both been there. Um so so basically
I don't know. I mean you're a
whistleblower. You I mean
>> Ted
>> Don't you What did you Go ahead. When I
when I blew the whistle,
it was in December of 2007
and I was unprepared for the media storm
that that ensued. Um, I gave an
interview to NPR. I I was in a hotel
room in Dallas, I remember, because my
boss had summoned me there to fire me. I
was at Deote and Touch. I ended up suing
them and I won. Um, but he summoned me
to Dallas to fire me. And before I went
into the office, you know, knowing this
was going to be a bad day, I gave this
interview to NPR.
And um, Senator Roy Blunt was the other
guest on the show. He was uh, at the
time the chairman of the Senate
Intelligence Committee and he said just
straight out,
"I want to see you hang from a tree."
And I thought, "Oh my god, this is this
is the chairman of the intelligence
committee and he's calling for me to be
executed or lynched.
I mean, at least if you're executed, you
get a trial, right?" And I thought, "Oh,
I this is this is going to be way worse
than I thought it was." And so I can
understand what she's going through
right now. you you speak the truth
because you believe that that the
American people or in the the case of
this woman, the Israeli people deserve
the truth, right? You see your role as a
whistleblower as one of keeping the
government honest
and then the response is to call for
your death.
So, I know exactly what she's going
through. This is going to be a very
difficult road and and it's going to be,
you know, it's going to be years. It may
be forever
before they appreciate what it is that
she did. I appreciate what it is that
she did, but she's she's in for a real
[__] storm.
>> John, I I've always wanted to ask you
this question, and I'm glad it this
comes up now. um when you when when you
know that like there's going to be uh
you know this big [__] show and it's
going to big media [__] storm around you
>> and [clears throat] it's going to be
basically it's going to come down to
people who are going to say good for
John Kuryaku for exposing torture. Thank
God for him versus people who are like
[__] him. He betrayed his oath. Um you
know what matters is we got to protect
the secrets of the US government.
you're kind of take you're kind of
placing a bet right on on that a sizable
majority or maybe at least a good plur
uh you know plurality of the American
people are good people that they're
going to see the obvious moral choice
here um that of of which what's right
what's more important is not to is being
opposed to torture and stopping torture
that's more important than safeguarding
government secrets that are basically
secrets involving the fact that you're
torturing Um, were you were you ever
disappointed that the American people
didn't
respond more or like I mean I always
think like Ed Snowden he he
[clears throat] said that he was trying
to start this national conversation
about privacy and NSA surveillance and
like you know he was he wanted to give
the American people a chance to raise
hell and put pressure Congress and put a
stop to it. Obviously, the American
people fell down on the job and did not
do that. And we are worse off than we
were in 2013 when he did that. Um,
>> yeah,
>> LA Times, I was not disappointed. The
people of Los Angeles came to my
support. Um, and and and and I mean
canceled their subscriptions and they
were pissed and they're like that. The
people of LA like, you know, I I'm so
grateful to them.
>> That's awesome.
>> How did you feel about I mean, how did
it go? Like do you did you feel like you
know like okay it's it's kind of like up
to the public now? How do you feel like
they did if you had to give them a
grade?
>> I would I would give him a D. I really
would. It I mean now it's great. Now
it's it's you know an A minus or a B+.
It'll be it'll be an A when I get a
pardon. But but no, it in the beginning
in the beginning um
it's like the the whole government fell
on my head and I couldn't get I couldn't
get out from under it. And then I'm
facing, you know, 45 years in prison and
the FBI's following me and tap my phones
and they're intercepting my emails and
my friends stop talking to me and some
of my relatives stop talking to me. I'll
tell you what, my mom has my mom has
my mom was one of nine children and only
two are still alive. One lives in Greece
and the other lives in Youngsttown,
Ohio. And um I don't speak to him. And
the reason I don't speak to him is
because one of my cousins called him
when I blew the whistle and said, "We
have to step up for Johnny." All my
cousins call me Johnny. So she says, "We
have to step up for Johnny." And my
uncle said, I told him years ago that he
should just keep his big [__] mouth
shut. My own uncle said this. He said,
"What he brought on himself, he brought
on himself and that was it. He walked
away from me." And now it's like, "Well,
why why doesn't Johnny talk to me?
Johnny talked doesn't talk to you
because he knows what you said about him
in 2007 and he doesn't like or respect
you,
>> asshole."
>> Yeah.
>> Um, Mr. out straight says to uh I
thought to you I thought your advice on
depression you gave on your own show
Deep Focus was very good and poant maybe
share it with the viewers here Ted's
input would be interesting too
>> somebody asked me I do Q&As's for deep
focus um oh once a week or once or two
weeks every two weeks whenever somebody
puts a question in the in the chat like
we have here um we we pull it out and I
do a 30 45 minute session just answering
questions so somebody asked me the other
day how I dealt with the depression and
I said frankly the easy answer is that
my life was saved by by 10 milligrams
every day of venaxine effect literally
saved my life. I also had something
called um transcranial magnetic therapy
which was incredible. It it was
brilliant, fantastic.
Um
but you know, every once in a while like
like everybody you find yourself falling
into depression for one reason or
another. Sometimes there's no reason.
Sometimes I just wake up and I feel a
little bit depressed. Maybe it's a dream
that I had that I don't even remember
what it was. And so what I said on the
on deep focus was you got to put
yourself first. And maybe that means
taking a couple of hours and going for a
long walk, you know, listen to music. Uh
go to a movie,
call a friend, [clears throat]
>> something, anything to distract
yourself.
>> Get out of your head.
>> Just get out of your head. Exactly. And
for me, that actually has worked.
>> Yeah. I mean, I've never been on on
drugs, on meds. Um I I kind of just
well, I've never it's never been
suggested to me, so therefore it's not
likely been a choice. Um I did um I did
talk therapy for years. Um and uh I was
diagnosed with uh PTSD over the LA Times
thing. Um
>> without a doubt.
>> And uh
>> I would be shocked if you told me that
you didn't have PTSD from the LA Times.
>> For sure. Um and and and I think that
the therapist was really shocked by just
how much out and she was very
experienced. Um EMDR turned out to be
really helpful for me.
>> Yeah, I've heard very good things about
EMDR.
>> So I I strongly recommend that. Um I'm
not I don't look I don't suffer from
sort of chemical depression at all. Um
I'm not one of those people who I'm a
pretty upbeat person. So for me it's
situational. If something really really
[__] bad happens to me or someone I
care about.
>> Yeah.
>> Then I can, you know, like when I was
caregiving for my mother who was dying
of Alzheimer's for years. That was rough
because I'm an only child. It was just
me and her. There were no other
relatives. Um I was, you know, they knew
they got to know me at LaGuardia at the
same little gate that flew to Dayton. It
was like, "Oh, Mr. Raw, nice to see you
again." I'm like, "Uhhuh."
Just trudging along.
>> Yeah. Depression's not been my problem.
My problem has been anxiety, but it's
paralyzing anxiety. Paralyzing. You
know, I went to see this um this shrink.
I only saw her one time because I didn't
like her, but um her entire practice is
just [__] up former CIA people. So,
she's cleared so you can speak freely
and all that stuff. She probably rats
you out to the agency anyway. But I I
went to see her one time and she said
that um she said, "I find it fascinating
that you have no PTSD
from the agency. You have no PTSD
from um prison,
>> but you have crippling [snorts]
PTSD from your divorce."
>> And I said, "Yeah." I said I that I
could have predicted that because they
teach us in training not to trust
anybody and I allowed myself to trust
one person.
>> Well, and I you know it's not a great
it's not a great Julia Roberts movie and
I I like Julia but Sleeping with the
Enemy is a great name for a movie about
a [__] up marriage.
>> Got that right.
>> That's literally what you're doing and
it's like it's really disturbing. It's
one thing to be like, you know, the
[__] whether it's the agency or, you
know, the newspaper publisher, but
they're outside of your house.
>> This is like you can't even go into your
happy home and be left the [__] alone.
>> No, no, no. And then you get the
chairman of the Senate Intelligence
Committee saying that you should be
executed,
>> which did nothing for my mood.
>> That's always, by the way, very bizarre
to me when like really highprofile
people punch down like that. Tom Tols
was the long-standing editorial
cartoonist at the Washington Post. At
one point he did a cartoon the chairman
of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the whole
joint chiefs of staff. They drafted a
letter calling for to poor Tom fired
from his job.
He didn't like his little cartoon. I'm
like, YOU GOT BIG MILITARY GUYS like
invade foreign countries all the time
and you're scared of a cartoonist? My
when my first book was coming out, um my
editor said, "Hey, let's ask George
Tennant for a for a blurb." And I said,
'George Tennant's not going to send a
blurb. He hates me and I hate him. No,
no, let's ask anyway. So they reach out
and uh and George Tennant writes back
and says, "I wouldn't do anything for
that asshole." And I said, "That's the
blurb."
>> Yeah.
>> Let's let's publish that on the back
cover. And they were like, "No, no, no.
We can't do that. This isn't a joke.
It's a serious book. Like, all
[laughter] right,
>> humor. Okay. You can never really have
enough humor. We got to talk about
Africa. Um before we wrap up here at the
top of the hour.
>> Yeah.
>> Tanzania. So, um I did decided to So, uh
there's riots. Um once again, we have
another [__] up election. President
Samya Suhu Hassan, first female
president of Tanzania, um just took
office um with 98% of the vote. I
suppose it's possible for someone to be
super super super super super popular,
but that doesn't appear to be the case
there. And the people of Tanzania
totally seem to not think that's the
case. Um
>> there's riots going on. Everything's
closed down. There's martial law. Um
over a thousand protesters have
apparently been gunned down in the
streets. The word is that bodies are
piling up on the streets and uh the
repression is rampant. Even the Pope has
chimed in. Um, so John, I'm kind of
like, okay, so ideologically, I wanted
to know sort of who's what here, right?
So, um, Samya Sulu Hassan is from this
long-standing ruling party that's been
in charge of Tanzania ever since
independence pretty much. And, uh, it's
easy to say, well, this is obviously a
[__] um, you know, election has to
be,
>> right? That said, I was like the thing,
you know, but I always get suspicious
when American media, let's say, well,
the opposition party, Chadima, has been
banned and they quote them. I was like,
well, who is this opposition? And it's
really uncomfortable for my side. I hate
this as a leftist, but basically the
opposition is center right
>> and Hassan is a lefty like a basically
African pan-African uh liberationist uh
you know, sort of out of in the Gaddafi
mold. Mhm.
>> So, it's the uncomfortable place to be
where the autocrat
>> I'm more sympathetic ideologically to
the autocrat and the uh and the person
who's being suppressed is the center
right, which I absolutely despise.
>> Yes.
>> What the [__] Anyway, um what do you
make of what's going on in Tanzania?
>> Um I think that that the Tanzanians
wanted to experiment again with um
authoritarianism.
thinking that it's like the 60s or 70s
all over again. It's not. And uh and
people are taken to the streets. A
thousand dead so far, [clears throat]
I think is uh they've gotten they've
gotten off easy. I think that uh when
the Pope weighs in, it's because things
are going to get a lot worse.
[clears throat] Excuse me.
And um I think this is the the
beginning, Ted, of um of uh political
upheaval that we're going to see in
Tanzania. You know, in the United
States, at least in the US government,
there's there's long been this belief
that that um Tanzania is one of those
democratic or pseudocratic
West African
countries that we can rely on. And it's
not. It's not. it it has these fascist
tendencies just like so many other
countries have and uh I think it's going
to get worse before it gets any better.
>> Um are we going to see some sort some
equivalent of an African spring?
>> You know what? I hadn't thought of that
but that's absolutely possible. Sure.
It's absolutely possible
>> with a ripple effect over postc colonial
Africa.
>> And and people people get to a point
where they just they can't take it
anymore. And and if you're hungry and
you're oppressed, the only place to go
is the street
>> because I mean the center of gravity,
right? Like in the postc colonial era
was this sort of these, you know, former
black liberation movements um that
basically took over. Then we went into
second and third generation like the
sons and daughters of those uh sons and
grandchildren of those leaders uh who
were charismatic in the 1960s and 70s.
And then the corruption got really out
of control and now it's fullblown.
Right. There's no there's not much left
except just the slogans from that
period.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's right. That is right.
>> Well guys, thanks everyone for tuning
in. Just a reminder, please contribute
to Robbie Aid. Uh it is I'm putting it
up on the screen.
Givego.comwestglacaming.
Um, we are here Monday through Friday,
9:00 am Eastern time. Uh, little
housekeeping. John and I will be back
here Wednesday at 9:00 am. Showtime will
be on Thursday, but Thursday, John,
you're out.
>> I'm out.
>> So, friend of the show, and my best
friend, Scott Stantis, uh, the editorial
cartoonist for the Chicago Tribune, will
be sitting in for John on Thursday
morning at 9:00 a.m. And John will be
back on Friday, rested and ready, I
hope. And, um, we're looking forward to
all that. Thanks. Uh, please stay tuned
for the TMI show with me, Ted R, and
Manila Chan. That's coming up right
after this. And, uh, you can just, if
you're in the Rumble chat, it'll just
steal you and TAKE YOU WAY AWAY and you
can never escape. Well, maybe that's not
quite true.
>> Enjoy.
>> All right. Thanks everyone and take
care. Now I Now I need to I need to hit
our little end stream thing. Oh, yeah.
No, I found it. Yay. Okay. Bye.
>> [music]
[music]